

Chicago, IL USA

□ (224) 258-2804 | Scontact@rasheedsaad.com | Www.rasheedsaad.com | Srashee

Summary.

I'm currently a Software Artisan at Accenture writing software for business products. I'm passionate about building, tinkering and making things better. I have experience developing on embedded systems and cloud technologies. I'm also attending University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign for Computer Science part time.

Work Experience

Accenture Industry X Apr 2021 - Present

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Scaled out a Smart City data ingestion pipeline using AWS, Terraform, Kubernetes and Helm.
- Deployed, managed and developed on multiple EKS clusters on AWS.
- Deployed microservice based web application that uses Elixir, Docker, Kafka, Redis, Elasticsearch, Postgres, Presto, NodeJS and Vault.

Motorola Solutions Secure Products Group

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

Jan 2018 - Apr 2021

- · Developed encryption software and security related features for the Motorola's next generation radio. Developed software across multiple teams across multiple countries and built solutions for cross team development.
- Developed and tested features for public safety related infrastructure.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER I

- · Developed test code for IoT TCP/UDP Servers in C that allowed for automated testing in an embedded environment.
- Helped design and build automated infrastructure and tooling for embedded devices.

Education

University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

Urbana-Champaign, Illinois

M.S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2019 - Present

· Relevant Courses: Distributed Systems (Cloud Computing), Parallel Programming, Theory and Practice of Data Cleaning and Text Information Systems.

Northern Illinois University

Dekalb, Illinois

2015 - 2017

B.S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- · Distinction: Cum Laude
- · Relevant Courses: Data Structures, Algorithms, UNIX, Networking, Databases, iOS Mobile Programming, Assembler Mainframe, Java, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture and Systems

Skills_

- Languages: C, C++, Python, Swift, SQL, Haskell, Javascript, YAML, and Scripting(Shell, PS1, Batch)
- Tools: Git, Docker, GDB, ARM debugger, npm, Clearcase, Jenkins, Github Actions, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Terraform, Artifactory, Conan, Jupyter, AWS, CMake, EKS, and EC2
- Platforms: AWS, Azure, Windows, Linux, ARM, and RHEL
- Q. Embedded: GPIO, USB, Serial, RS232, and SPI Interfaces
- Security: Experience working with encryption algorithms, key management and general understanding of web security

Projects

Causal Data Mining

CS410: Text Information Systems

ITERATIVE TOPIC MODELING WITH TIME SERIES FEEDBACK

October 2020

- · Worked with a team to develop a system in Python to analyze historical data and build graphical associations with historical events.
- The project and code is an open-sourced research project available for viewing here.

Google Extension Google Chrome Store

MINIMALIST Feb. 2019 - Present

• Developed and maintain a minimal note taking application for Google Chrome.

• Available for download in the Google Chrome Store.

ACM WCS Mentorship Program

MENTOR

University of Illinois at UC

May. 2020

• Mentored an Ungraduate Computer Science student.

• Met virtually on a regular cadence to help matriculation during the COVID 19 Pandemic.

Motorola YPG SCH Motorola Solutions

SOCIAL BRANCH LEAD

Jan. 2020 - Apr 2021

· Led a team to setup events for Motorola social events.

- Event planning for virtual events during the pandemic.
- Event planning for social in-person events for 500 attendants.

Motorola Hackathon Schaumburg, Illinois

TECHNICAL ENABLEMENT LEAD

Jan. 2019 - Apr. 2019

- · Led a team to setup required technical infrastructure for hackathon, hosting approximately 100 participants.
- Team enabled participants to use GitLab, GitHub, Cloud Instances alongside proprietary Motorola hardware.

iOS Application Northern Illinois University

UniBoard Dec. 2016 - Feb. 2018

- Developed a social media iOS application in Swift 3 that allowed university students to sign up and communicate publicly through posts and images.
- Used Firebase for the back-end and data store to allow users to comment and like other user's posts.